## **Michael Woodruff**

### User Experience Designer & Front End Developer

michaelwoodruff.com • michael.woodruff@gmail.com • (513) 410-1485

#### Summary

An application designer who focuses on creating elegant yet usable interactive experiences that engage users, while also communicating a timely effective message. Understands the need to balance the conflicting agendas of the client's business goals, user's expectations, limitations of a chosen technology, and a project's budget constraints. A firm believer that it's not only just how the software looks, but also how intuitive it is to use.

#### **Specialties**

Sass/SCSS User Experience Design Front End Architecture User Interface Design Patterns Web Standards Less Style Guides JavaScript Git/GitHub Design Systems AJAX Bootstrap Wireframing Semantic HTM Backbone **Usability Testing** Progressive Enhancement HTML5 **iQuery** Information Architecture CSS3 Sketch SEO/Analytics Photoshop **Prototyping** Designing in the Browser A/B Testing Illustrator Visual Design

#### Experience

OCTOBER 2009 - PRESENT (7 years)

#### Kalio Commerce — Front End Developer & User Experience Architect

- Design and built the front-end architecture that is leveraged across all clients on the Kalio SasS platform
- Pioneered responsive design with clients and within the organization
- Consulted with clients to implement their service onto the Kalio SasS platform
- Established user experience principles for the redesign of Kalio Site Manager
- Create Style Guides and code samples for both clients and internal use
- Provided leadership on UX and front-end development for all developers and designers
- Create wireframes for design discussions on all e-commerce pages
- Lead the visual design with the client
- Performed A/B testing to increase conversion
- Leverage analytics to inform usage patterns and increase conversion

Clients: Republic of Tea • Beren Shoes, Inc. • Acorn Media • A.M. Leonard • Positive Promotions • Taylor Corporation • Discount Ramps • Touch of Class • Hale Groves • Travers • Jack Stack Barbecue

JUNE 2009 - OCTOBER (5 Months)

# **Construction Software Technologies** — Front End Developer & Designer

JUNE 2009 - OCTOBER (5 Months)

**Bridge Worldwide** — Experience Planner

Clients: Kroger • Procter & Gamble

AUGUST 2004 - APRIL 2008 (3 years 9 months)

#### **Haverstick Consulting** — User Experience Designer

Clients: Kentucky Lottery • Greater Cincinnati Water Works • Ethicon • Basco

OCTOBER 2003 - AUGUST 2004 (11 months)

#### **Fusion Alliance** — Information Architect

Clients: ATA Airlines • Roche Diagnostics

AUGUST 2004 - APRIL 2008 (1 year 2 months)

#### **Contractor** — Web Designer

Clients: FreeMarkets, Inc. • LexisNexis

MAY 1996 - FEBRUARY 2002 (5 years 10 months)

#### **Digineer** — User Interface Designer

Clients: Bank One • Bayer • Johnson & Johnson • Patterson Dental

#### Education

**The Ohio State University**— B.S. Business Administration

#### Portfolio

View my portfolio online at http://michaelwoodruff.com

#### Recommendations

- "Woody brings a creative flair to every project he works on. His drive to understand user behaviors and to design the best interface for that user group is unparalleled. He routinely impressed me with his creativity and ability to model complex user interfaces."
- Joe Walter, Managing Director, Haverstick Consulting, Inc., managed Michael at Haverstick Consulting
- "When I was just getting into Web standards, Woody was my go-to guy for answers. He still is. His extensive knowledge is applied in the sites he designs, which makes him an asset to any client who desires a site incorporating the latest in usability, accessibility, and design principles. He's also very generous in imparting his experience to colleagues. I'd consider Woody to be an asset to any team I was on."
- **Lisa Ruff**, Senior Consultant / e-Learning Instructional Designer, Haverstick Government Solutions, Inc., worked with Michael at Haverstick Consulting
- "Woody brought surprising depth and breadth to his position with Haverstick. He had a strong eye for graphic design, and excelled in "Web 2.0" interaction --paying careful attention to interactivity and behavior as much as raw aesthetics. He also did an excellent job of keeping current and sharing the latest and greatest."
- Alex Hart, Practice Manager, Haverstick Consulting, managed Michael at Haverstick Consulting
- "Mike "gets it" when it comes to standards based web design/development. His deep experience comes across to clients very well. He has excellent communication skills and is willing to go the extra mile. I highly recommend Mike."

 Steve Daly, Director of Technology, Haverstick Consulting, Inc., managed Michael at Haverstick Consulting

"I worked with Michael Woodruff (aka Woody) during his stint at Haverstick Consulting. He is a very fun person to work with and a great contributor to the team. He makes an effort to understand Customer's needs and delivers the product to their satisfaction. He is always up to date on the technical trends/aspects of User Interface design (and his Apple gadgets). It was a pleasure to work with Woody."

- Gauri Kodkani, Senior Consultant, Haverstick Consulting, worked with Michael at Haverstick Consulting

"I was involved with Michael on gathering design requirements and software specifications for a client project. Michael was extremely thorough and relies heavily on his strong client skills to drive discussions to a distinct solution. He was able to create wireframes, site maps, and several design mockups in a timely manner, despite a full workload. His artistry in design achieves that rare balance of both broad appeal and intuitive user interaction. He has extensive familiarity with market trends which enables him to frame prospective client solutions, producing a mutual basis of communication."

 Clifford Adams, Senior Software Developer, Haverstick Business Solutions, worked directly with Michael at Haverstick Consulting